(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-10T01:38:04.282652",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
I was always looking for a beacon in the dark times
my guiding light.
all the captive dreams i held so dear,
waiting for a moment to live without fear.
ever since i met you, we've been living in the sunshine,
so warm, so bright.
my heart is full, the skies are clear,
the road goes on forever, we made it so far together.
this is our song,
a story forged in bonds.
a journey of the heart that goes on and on...
now i feel so free,
i can be who i am,
i know i'm not alone, i got a new life
in the rain, the wind, and the sunlight
you believed in me, and that's where it all began
now hope is everlasting
i can live my life with you, unchained.
遥か遠くから
From far, far away
辿り着いた
We have finally arrived
輝きたたえる
Shedding light and praising
よすがへ降り立つ
We land upon our haven
we're unchained.
i was shut away, i waited every day,
my whole world was so small (so small)
but here and now, it's like the walls just fall away;
i can see it all.
out here in the light with you,
it's such a perfect view;
blue skies and sunsets.
the joyful days that seem to fly,
the heartfelt moments and the good times,
and through all these years,
through tenderness and tears,
i found my way at last,
'cause i knew you were right here.
now i feel so free
i can be who i am.
i'm not afraid, 'cause even on a dark night,
i can feel the glow of the starlight.
now the world i see is as bright as you became.
i will cherish every moment,
this is what it means to live unchained.
don't cry, you can breathe free;
i'm here if you need me.
let go of all your heartache,
we made it through, it's the dawning of a new day
feel the world's embrace,
oh, what a joyful place
this is where i wanna be, so come with me; keep dreaming...
now i feel so free,
i can be who i am,
i know i'm not alone, i got a new life
in the rain, the wind, and the sunlight
What goes around
comes back around.
“Sit down and listen.”
Back in business to even up the score;
We lost the battle, but now we win the war.
Ah- This world of dull routines,
Living in monotony.
Can't escape it? Watch us, we'll break it.
The old rules do not apply (apply)
You better kiss them all goodbye (goodbye)
It's our turn, so stand aside,
Ain't nothing gonna stem this rising tide.
We're through with convention and being controlled,
We dish out revenge and we're serving it cold.
Yeah, yeah.
Don't you know what we been told?
That “what goes around will come back around,”
They tried to bury us, but we never stay down.
No more playing nice,
Now it's just an eye for an eye;
two wrongs are making it right.
We broke our chains, and now,
the world above is gonna come down
So come and get it!
We're coming around,
We're taking you down.
Shattered glass
and tattered walls,
We're coming fast,
gonna break it all.
Do you hear the sirens cry?
What a perfect lullaby,
'Cause we're taking over tonight.
Yeah.
Hey, hey! Wake up!
Them's the breaks.
You gotta reap what you sow, so it's time to pay.
All your games are uninspired,
We're here to light up a fire,
No more mandates, we can set the world ablaze.
Yeah, yeah.
Don't you know what people say?
That “what goes around will come back around,”
They tried to bury us, but we never stay down.
No more playing nice,
Now it's just an eye for an eye;
two wrongs are making it right.
We broke our chains, and now,
the world above is gonna come down so loud,
What goes around is coming
back 'round and 'round,
The world is never living this down,
So come and get it,
We're coming around,
We're taking you down.
[Uh, when we come around...]
We won't run, and we won't stop.
We're still not done coming out on top
[What comes around]
No more silence, no more fear,
Now the world will know we're here,
We'll make it abundantly clear:
What goes around
comes back around.
“BREAKOUT!!!!!”
Feel the rumble underground,
I'm the terror in your walls,
Lashing out until you crumble
Smoke and fire raining down,
Let the sky fall!
I'll eviscerate your darkened halls;
Till nothing's left of you at all!
With a cry of wrath, I will crush these chains
Until only your wreckage and ash remains.
A rebellious spark lights a blazing flame.
Let it rage, I come uncaged,
Screaming out into the shadows, I will break away
“LET ME OUT!”
“LET ME OUT! LET ME OUT!”
Melt away your grip of steel.
See the binding wearing thin
I will shatter your obsession
There is nothing left to feel
No delusions
From the hall of nightmares I ascend
And I will bring about your end
With a desperate cry, I will shatter fate
You can sound the alarms, but it's just too late
See the world reborn in a sea of flame
Let it dance, my only chance
Screaming out into the shadows, I will break away
Take back your maze of lies
I've seen the other side
The point of no return
This fire's gotta burn
Woah
Rise up and break out!
With a cry of wrath, I will crush these chains
Until only your wreckage and ash remains
A rebellious spark lights a blazing flame
Let it rage, I come uncaged
Screaming out into the shadows, I will break away
Breakout!
Ah! That was crazy!
Oh my gosh! I survived! I survived!
Get up, Biboo!
Ah! My spine!
Ah, sorry!
We did it! We did it!
First song, done!
Fuwawa! Mococo! Shiori!
自己紹介！ Yes! Okay!
Self-introductions! Yes! Okay!
Shiori!
Shiori Novella here at your service, hololive's archiver!
And today, I'm with... all of Advent!
Yeah! And next up, let's go!
Okay, I'm pumped! I'm pumped! I'm pumped, let's go!
Biboo, Biboo!
Koseki Bijou, the sparkling gem of hololive English, Advent!
Kiri-kiri, rock on!
Yeah! Rock on! Next, next!
My turn!
Hi darlings, this is hololive English Advent's devilish diva,
the one, the only, Nerissa Ravencroft!
Happy to be here with my girls today! Next up!
I'm Fuwawa! And I'm Mococo!
Together we're FuwaMoco! Bau bau!
I'm Mococo! Together we're FuwaMoco! Bau bau!
And together we're... Advent!!!
Today is a very, very special day!
Yes, it is!
'Cause we are celebrating our half-anniversary!
And we're the third gen, our six months...
It's so special!
And look around us at the stage!
All the fire, the balloons, the lights!
It's very Advent-esque!
Yeah, so edgy! It is!
There's a bunch of cracks on the ground because I... I tripped everywhere!
And I made the cool crack!
We'll just adjust to her.
No fighting! No fighting!
I'm almost after...
Wow, we have some very special things planned,
especially a surprise at the end today, so please stick around, okay?
Yeah! Surprise!
So, shall we get going to our next songs, baby?
Let's do it! Bau bau! Yippee!
動き出す身体の奥には
Deep inside this body starting to move,
生まれたての螺旋が騒ぐ
a freshly born spiral stirs.
ほら
Look...
あじけない つまらない
Dull and wearisome,
この世界の端
from the edge of this world...
見下ろす
Looking down,
あなたはだれ？
who are you?
目の前捲られてゆくの
This future is being rolled back before my eyes...
触れられない未来
this future that cannot be touched.
昨日だった世界は
The world that was yesterday
予定調和ばかりだけど
is nothing but pre-established harmony,
まだ
yet,
絶望？ 希望？ すれすれ紙一重
despair and hope are paper-thinly close.
それも愛しいんだ
Even that is precious,
見えないとしても
even if it cannot be seen.
暗がり そっと
The darkness, so softly...
君の手をひいて
pulls you by the hand.
走り出す呼吸に紛れて
Slipping into my racing breath,
剥がれ落ちてゆく世界は
the world peeling away...
間違い探しみたいだね
seems like a game of 'spot the difference'.
本物はどれか答えて
Tell me, which is the real one?
ほら
Look...
あたたかい 柔らかい
Warm and tender,
世界の勝手
the selfishness of this world...
差し出す
Reaching out,
あなたはだれ？
who are you?
飛び交う雑音が
The fluttering noise
いま心ごとぼやかして
now blurs my entire heart,
明日にはきっと
and by tomorrow, it'll surely be
コントロール不能だけど
beyond control...
嗚呼
Ah,
絶望？ 希望？ 君？ 僕？ 裏？ 表？
despair, hope, you, me, inside, outside...
不確かさ歌って
I sing of uncertainty
その意味を探すよ
and search for its meaning.
神様、ちょっと
Dear God, please...
僕の手をひいて
pull me by my hand.
生まれた価値を
Even if the value of being born
与えられなくとも
is never given to us,
重ねた混沌と日々は
these accumulated days of chaos
答えをくれる
will give us our answer.
目の前捲られてゆくの
This future is being rolled back before my eyes...
触れられない未来
this future that cannot be touched.
昨日だった世界は
The world that was yesterday
予定調和ばかりだけど
is nothing but pre-established harmony,
まだ
yet,
絶望？ 希望？ すれすれ紙一重
despair and hope are paper-thinly close.
それも愛しいんだ
Even that is precious,
君が選ぶなら
if you're the one to choose it.
暗がり ぎゅっと
In the darkness, so tightly...
君の手をひいて
pulling you by your hand.
リンッ リンッ リンッ！ おはよう wake up
Rin rin rin! Good morning, wake up!
ドキ・ドキ☆モーニング
Doki Doki Morning!
うわーーー！
Woah!
ぱっつん ぱっつん 前髪 ぱっつん cutie style
Straight-cut, straight-cut, straight-cut bangs, cutie style
やっぱ 一直線なら 一等賞よ チョーすごい！
After all, if it's a straight line, it's first prize, so super awesome!
今日 Lip あっち？ こっち？ そっち？ どっち？
Today's lipstick, that way? This way? Over there? Which way?
Which? チョッチ？ ウォッチ 今何時？
Which? A tiny bit? Watch, what time is it now?
集合 集合 放課後集合 party time
Gather up, gather up, meet up after school, party time
だって 女子会参加で ガールズトークよ チョーヤバい！
'Cause it's a girls' night out and girls' talk, so super crazy!
今日 VIP あっち？ こっち？ そっち？ どっち？
Today's VIP, that way? This way? Over there? Which way?
Which? チョッチ？ ウォッチ 今何時？
Which? A tiny bit? Watch, what time is it now?
知らないフリは キライ！キライ！
I hate pretending not to know! I hate it!
知らない世界 見たい！見たい！
I want to see the unknown world! I want to see it!
4次元 5次元 期待！期待！
4th dimension, 5th dimension, expectations, expectations!
10% 背伸びしたい！したい！ よね？
I want to stretch myself by 10%! I want to, right?
リンッ リンッ リンッ！ おはよー wake up
Ring, ring, ring! Good morning, wake up
お・ね・が・い！ ちょ待って！ ちょ待って！
P-l-e-a-s-e! Wait a sec! Wait a sec!
ring ring ring ! あせらず hurry up
Ring, ring, ring! Take your time, hurry up
バ・タ・バ・タ☆モーニング
Chaotic, chaotic morning
リンッ リンッ リンッ！ あわてず make up
Ring, ring, ring! Don't rush, make up
お・ね・が・い！ ちょ待って！ ちょ待って！
P-l-e-a-s-e! Wait a sec! Wait a sec!
ring ring ring ! today は version up
Ring, ring, ring! Today is a version up
ド・キ・ド・キ☆モーニング
Heart-throbbing, heart-throbbing morning
すっぴん すっぴん メガネがヘアピン funny face
No makeup, no makeup, glasses as a hairpin, funny face
だけど 3秒待ってね そっこー変身 チョーはやい！
But wait three seconds, instant transformation, super fast!
今日 Rap あっち？ こっち？ そっち？ どっち？
Today's rap, that way? This way? Over there? Which way?
Which? チョッチ？ ウォッチ 今何時？
Which? A tiny bit? Watch, what time is it now?
知らないフリは キライ！キライ！
I hate pretending not to know! I hate it!
知らない世界 見たい！見たい！
I want to see the unknown world! I want to see it!
4次元 5次元 期待！期待！
4th dimension, 5th dimension, expectations, expectations!
10% 背伸びしたい！したい！ よね？
I want to stretch myself by 10%! I want to, right?
リンッ リンッ リンッ！ おはよー wake up
Ring, ring, ring! Good morning, wake up
お・ね・が・い！ ちょ待って！ ちょ待って！
P-l-e-a-s-e! Wait a sec! Wait a sec!
ring ring ring ! あせらず hurry up
Ring, ring, ring! Take your time, hurry up
バ・タ・バ・タ☆モーニング
Chaotic, chaotic morning
リンッ リンッ リンッ！ あわてず make up
Ring, ring, ring! Don't rush, make up
お・ね・が・い！ ちょ待って！ ちょ待って！
P-l-e-a-s-e! Wait a sec! Wait a sec!
ring ring ring ! today は version up
Ring, ring, ring! Today is a version up
ド・キ・ド・キ☆モーニング
Heart-throbbing, heart-throbbing morning
リンッ リンッ リンッ！ おはよー wake up
Ring, ring, ring! Good morning, wake up
お・ね・が・い！ ちょ待って！ ちょ待って！
P-l-e-a-s-e! Wait a sec! Wait a sec!
ring ring ring ! あせらず hurry up
Ring, ring, ring! Take your time, hurry up
バ・タ・バ・タ☆モーニング
Chaotic, chaotic morning
リンッ リンッ リンッ！ あわてず make up
Ring, ring, ring! Don't rush, make up
お・ね・が・い！ ちょ待って！ ちょ待って！
P-l-e-a-s-e! Wait a sec! Wait a sec!
ring ring ring ! today は version up
Ring, ring, ring! Today is a version up
ド・キ・ド・キ☆モーニング
Heart-throbbing, heart-throbbing morning
リンッ リンッ リンッ！ おはよー wake up
Ring, ring, ring! Good morning, wake up
ド・キ・ド・キ☆モーニング
Heart-throbbing, heart-throbbing morning
流れてく時の中ででも 気だるさが ほらグルグル回って
Even in the midst of flowing time, look, listlessness is spinning round and round.
私から離れる心も 見えないわ そう知らない
Even my heart drifting away from me is invisible, yes, I don't know.
自分から動くこともなく 時の隙間に流され続けて
Without moving on my own, continuing to drift in the gaps of time.
知らないわ 周りのことなど 私は私 それだけ
I don't know about my surroundings, I am just me, that's all.
夢見てる？ 何も見てない？ 語るも無駄な 自分の言葉？
Are you dreaming? Seeing nothing? Are my own words useless to speak?
悲しむなんて 疲れるだけよ 何も感じず 過ごせばいいの
Getting sad is just tiring, it's fine to get through without feeling anything.
過ごせばいいの
I should just spend my days feeling nothing.
戸惑う言葉 与えられても
Even if I am given puzzling words,
自分の心 ただ上の空
My heart is just somewhere up in the air.
もしも私から 動くのならば
If I were to make a move myself,
すべて変えるのなら 黒にする
If it would change everything, I'd paint it black.
こんな自分に 未来はあるの？
Is there a future for someone like me?
こんな世界に 私はいるの？
Do I even exist in a world like this?
今切ないの？ 今悲しいの？
Am I in pain now? Am I sad now?
自分の事も わからないまま
Without even understanding myself,
歩むことさえ 疲れるだけよ
Even just walking is exhausting.
人のことなど 知りもしないわ
I don't care to know anything about others.
こんな私も 変われるのなら
If even someone like me could change,
もし変われるのなら 白になる
If I could change, I would become white.
流れてく 時の中ででも
Even within the flowing passage of time,
気だるさが ほらグルグル回って
Weariness just keeps spinning around and around.
私から 離れる心も 見えないわ
I can't even see my heart drifting away from me.
そう知らない
That's right, I don't know.
自分から 動くこともなく
Without making a move myself,
時の隙間に 流され続けて
I continue to drift through the gaps of time.
知らないわ 周りのことなど
I don't care to know about my surroundings.
私は私 それだけ
I am just myself, and that is all.
夢見てる？ 何も見てない？
Are you dreaming? Or seeing nothing at all?
語るも無駄な 自分の言葉
My own words are pointless to speak.
悲しむなんて 疲れるだけよ
Grieving is just exhausting.
何も感じず 過ごせばいいの
I should just spend my days feeling nothing.
戸惑う言葉 与えられても
Even if I am given puzzling words,
自分の心 ただ上の空
My heart is just somewhere up in the air.
もしも私から 動くのならば
If I were to make a move myself,
すべて変えるのなら 黒にする
If it would change everything, I'd paint it black.
動くのならば 動くのならば
If I make a move, if I make a move,
すべて壊すわ すべて壊すわ
I'll destroy everything, I'll destroy everything.
悲しむならば 悲しむならば
If I am to grieve, if I am to grieve,
私の心 白く変われる？
Can my heart change to white?
あなたのことも 私のことも
About you, and about me,
すべてのことも まだ知らないの
I still don't know anything at all.
重い目蓋を 開けたのならば
If I were to open my heavy eyelids,
すべて壊すのなら 黒になれ！
If it's to destroy everything, let it turn black!
Yay! Thank you!
Thank you!
Dokidoki Maimai! Dokidoki Maimai!
Maimai, Maimai...
Oh my god! That was so...
That was scary, but that was awesome!
Nerve-wracking!
We actually got to perform a special song together too!
Yeah! We performed "Kami-iro Awase."
Which is from Danganronpa.
And I actually, I love this song, so I picked it. Sorry!
That's okay!
But I've always wanted to sing it with you because it's one of my favorite songs...
...but it gives me really, really bad luck every time I listen to it.
I'm the bad luck of us!
Really bad things happen to me, so I thought maybe...
...if I sing it with Shiori, then it'll fix my luck!
Luck! Unlucky...
And we also sang "Bad Apple!!" together, right?
You can play "Bad Apple!!" on anything, including Advent's 3D debut!
And "Bad Apple!!" is actually the song we wanted to do together...
...all the way since before we broke out of the cell, right?
Yeah, we finally got to do it!
And not just the five of us, but it was extra special...
...with all the shadows behind us!
It was kind of like the original MV, right? It was so cool!
Shadows!
And well, maybe that's not just the end of everything...
Wait, there's more?
Oh yes! Next, we have something special.
Something special... surprise!
I'm sinking! I'm sinking, hurry! Please hurry, I'm sinking!
Noooo! Wait, wait, wait!
シオシオ
Shio-Shio
リサリサ
Risa-Risa
魔界乃番犬シスターズ★
Underworld Guard Dog Sisters★
この世界に爆誕 “BAU”DOL です
Born into this world, we are "BAU"DOLs!
BAUBAU!!
シオリ
Shiori!
ネリッサ (Nerissa!!)
Nerissa! (Nerissa!!)
SHIO+RISSAは (SHIORISSA!)
SHIO+RISSA is (SHIORISSA!)
シオリ
Shiori!
ネリッサ (Nerissa!!)
Nerissa! (Nerissa!!)
SHIO+RISSAは (SHIORISSA!)
SHIO+RISSA is (SHIORISSA!)
BAUBAU!!
Wake up したら君に Morning
When I wake up, it's morning with you
New な出会い 鼻利かせ Search して
Sniffing out new encounters, searching around
ドキドキ ドキドキ
Thump-thump, thump-thump
右に 左 BAU BAU BAU
To the right, to the left, BAU BAU BAU
悩んでいても来ちゃう Future
Even if you worry, the future will come
まずは目の前の道 Step して
First, take a step on the road ahead
Happy Lucky Happy
一緒に歩こうよ
Let's walk together
ドーナツの穴の中には
Inside the hole of a donut...
きっと きっと
...surely, surely...
夢が詰まってるから
...dreams are packed tight!
シオシオ
Shio-Shio
リサリサ
Risa-Risa
魔界乃番犬シスターズ★
Underworld Guard Dog Sisters★
2匹が揃えば もう大騒ぎ
When the two of us gather, it's total chaos!
もあもあ
More, more!
ハロハロ
Hello, hello!
迷わずに Go my way
Without hesitating, go my way!
君の絶対味方 “BAU”DOL です
I am your absolute ally, a "BAU"DOL!
この世界に爆誕 “BAU”DOL です
Born into this world, we are "BAU"DOLs!
BAUBAU!!
シオリ
Shiori!
ネリッサ (Nerissa!!)
Nerissa! (Nerissa!!)
SHIO+RISSAは (SHIORISSA!)
SHIO+RISSA is (SHIORISSA!)
シオリ
Shiori!
ネリッサ (Nerissa!!)
Nerissa! (Nerissa!!)
SHIO+RISSAは (SHIORISSA!)
SHIO+RISSA is (SHIORISSA!)
BAUBAU!!
お待たせ！
Thanks for waiting!
Moco's here to play
Woke up in the morning
I had a funny dream
I was a stone that had been thrown
No way back, I was all in
Lost in this game, I feel the strain
But I'm pulled back up by your gravity
Your gravity (Ha-a-a)
Biboo! Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one two three, BIBOO BIBOO
Come and test your luck, yeah we comin' in clutch, BIBOO BIBOO
Skipping stone in flight, take 'em out one-shot, BIBOO BIBOO
Better hit quicksave 'cause...
Moco's here to play!
Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one two three, BIBOO BIBOO
Hit 'em with a one-two-three, BIBOO BIBOO
Come and test your luck, yeah we comin' in clutch, BIBOO BIBOO
Skipping stone in flight, take 'em out one-shot, BIBOO BIBOO
Come and help me fight
Get on up, let's go, just me and you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes, make a wish
One more shot, I will not miss
ROCK IN!
Moco Moco!
Lingering in him
He's made of sin, nothing in the abyss he calls a soul
(Eating at him, there's a rage; He hunts to feel any little thing)
He's desperate, sure - but even more he won't live another day
(Picked the wrong victim and cried "God spare me oh please!")
As light left his eyes, she contemplates how her heart it aches
The memory of him keeps her warm and safe, in her bed there lies
A pile of bones and echoes of a love that's dead and gone
(Seen it all, been done before, cliche but it's real... history)
Repeating Over, over again
You are all the same in the end
Oh you're restricted
(In the bitter end)
You've no conviction
Tell me your story now
Now!
Lalalala lala~
Set it in stone Let it be known By those who pay attention
Restricted by your own hand, the end
Aaah
Sniff, sniff, sniff
Oh, I know this smell! It belongs to my darling!
Much more of it, and I'll be smothering you in kisses!
Oh, wait, my love, I can't stop, Fuwawa's almost there...
Think my body might overheat
'Cause when I look at you, my heart can't help but skip a beat
Your eyes that shine and dazzle, soft lips that get me frazzled
The lovely way you smile (ooh)
Past the point of no turning back
Yeah, I've been struck by cupid, all my sense goes boo-boo-boo-boo-boom!
This overflowing love's so haaaard!
Feel it coursing through me like a heat that I can't disregard
Hello precious kitten, you can drop the coy disguise
Don't you turn away from me, just look me in the eyes
Forecast is clear skies, BAUBAU sensor's all powered up!
Ope! Hehe.
I've found you!
Here I am, bursting at the seams to tell you how I'm feeling
Love you, love you - baby, won't you marry me
You're my one, my only, shining princess
Yeah, you know I won't let you go!
Wedding bells are ringing and the guests are waiting
God himself can't stop me, yeah I'll make ya mine
We'll have a perfect honeymoon
You'll be mine, yeah, I'll getchu
Holic♡ for my waifu
CHU!
Advent Shuffle! / Shuffle Medley!
I wanted to do this since our debut!
Were you surprised? / BAU BAU!
At first, we started with Fuwawa! / OYOME♡HOLIC!
BAU BAU! / BAU BAU!
I was so happy! It's really rare that another HoloMember is singing our song!
It's my song! / And it was so cute! Fuwawa was so cute!
Yeah! She was so cute!
And then right after... it was... Mococo's...
Born to be "BAU"DOL! / No, it was Shiori and Nerissa!
You guys rocked! / We did!
Yeah, you did! / I've always wanted to do this!
And after that was Biboo's...
I drove a car! I drove a car!
You did! / I drove a car! / You sure did!
I actually started like this... beep beep!
And then Shiori came in! / Yeah, I did!
And I was so happy because I love your song, Nerissa!
I know! / But I'm angry!
何で？
Why?
Because of those lyrics!
Eh?
You did this on purpose, Nerissa! How could you write something like that?
I just translated them from Japanese!
You did it on purpose! Nerissa! Nerissa!
You liked it! You liked it!
No, I didn't!
But it was so much fun being able to combine all of our songs into a medley like that!
That's something I've wanted to do for a long time, especially because of the Holo Shuffle, those are so fun!
So being able to have an Advent Shuffle... / Yeah!
...is so awesome!
But... I hate to say this, Advent...
What? What? What? Is it over? Why?
It's not over, right?
It's not over. That's not it, it's worse.
It's worse? / No!
We have to test something.
A test? / No, I didn't study! / Is it math, right?
We need to test our nakama power!
Oh my god! / Nakama power?
We've done a shuffle, we've done this performance...
...for almost a year now we've been together as a team.
Do we truly have the nakama no chikara?
Oh... / Yeah, I think we do!
Well, how should we test this nakama...
...nakama power?
I've got an anime on my side! / Show us the power of teamwork!
Teamwork!
Well, look behind us. What do you see?
Silhouettes! / Shadows! / I'm not gonna be scared!
There's some shadows behind us. They look like our silhouettes, but...
They are moving!
Ready, ready... okay.
Na na na na... watashi no watashi...
Thank you, thank you so much!
Okay, so... / What are we doing?
I've actually done a collab with Pokey to prepare this.
Wow! Pokey! / Pokey's here!
He is going to be giving us topics and we are going to have to create...
...with the shadows, with our bodies, whatever the topic given to us is.
Oh, okay! / Our bodies? / Ooh, nice!
We can't rely on our amazing appeal like usual.
We simply have to use only our shadows.
Our silhouettes, if you will.
So, Pokey, are you ready, Pokey? Give us the first prompt! / Oh!
Favorite animal / Our favorite animal!
Animal, animal! / Demon dogs, right? Demon dogs!
I like cats. / I like cats too. / Let's make cats!
Cat! Cat! Cat!
Yeah, but demon dogs are cool too.
I love my demon dogs!
I wanted to do a cat.
Why, why, why do you want to do a cat, though?
Yeah!
We'll make a cat, we'll make a cat.
Okay, we'll make a cat then.
Okay, how are we going to do this?
We got the ears.
Wait, wait! I'm just like, an giant...
How do we make a cat?
But I'm not tall enough. How do I get up there?
Did I mention we're timed? We have one minute!
We need to make a cat!
I'm going to be...
Shiori, we're making the head!
Okay, okay, this is the head. This is the head of the cat, somehow.
I'm going to be the... Oh, should I...
Should I be...
Yeah! I'm not tall enough to be the ear!
I'll be the ear. I'm going to be the ear.
Is this a cat?
Wait, we need ears! We need ears!
Okay, okay, there are ears. I'm the mouth. I'm the mouth.
Is this a cat yet?
It looks more like a... like a pig.
Meow! Meow!
I'm an ear! My head is an ear!
It's pretty good, it's pretty good!
Is this a cat?
Yeah, I think this is a cat!
Meow!
And then we need the tail!
Yeah, we've got the tail going!
Meow!
We did it! I think it's a very unique cat.
What do you think? I think this is 100%.
Yeah, come on! What do you think?
It's a cat from the underworld, okay? It's different.
Yeah, that's how it is.
100%! This is how it looks.
It's a cat! It's a cat!
Yeah! Don't judge us, we tried our best!
Let's move on to the next prompt!
Giant Face.
Oh, I got this! I got this! Let's make eyes, eyes!
Okay, okay, wait. Eyes, right?
Whoa! We can't see!
Get closer! Get closer!
Okay, okay, this is an eye. This is an eye.
This is also an eye.
Can someone else grab her other foot?
Okay, I got it. You got it.
This is the mouth, this is the mouth.
Mouth! Shiori, you got the other eye?
It's a mouth!
Okay, this is an eye, this is an eye.
Guys, don't hold her legs!
Go make something else on the face.
We need to make a wide smile.
Is this good?
I'm an ear! I'm an ear!
I'm an eyeball. No, no, this is what I look like.
Shiori, you're good. You look like the eyes.
Look like the eyes. I can be an ear, okay?
Oh, I'm an ear? You're an ear.
Oh, this is pretty good!
This is okay!
This is pretty good! This is a pretty good face.
Is it a face yet? I think it's pretty good.
Wait, hold the pose! Hold the pose!
Nerissa, can you scoot, scoot, scoot?
Yeah!
Oh, my god! That was definitely a face.
That was a good face!
Congrats! You want help?
No, I'm good.
What's the next one? Let's go!
Okay, what is it?
Advent. We have to write "Advent".
Oh! Who's letters?
Okay, one letter at a time, one letter at a time.
Let's start with A. Who wants to make A?
We've got to do this with A first. Tall people make A! Tall people make A!
I'm tall! You are tall indeed.
Someone needs to be short. Okay, that looks like an A!
An A! Okay, let's move to the next one.
D! D!
Oh, this should be easy.
Okay, okay.
Wait, are we backwards? Don't we need to...
No, they can flip it.
Oh! Someone needs to... Is this...
I need to be held! and then I can be the D part.
Is this D? I don't know, man.
I don't think this is working yet. Is this a ladder?
No, this is not working. Wait, what if we do a small D?
Just a lowercase D. Okay, lowercase D, lowercase D.
A lowercase D. That'll be easier. Someone just has to like go like this, right?
Like like this? No, someone needs to stand up.
Well, that's the bottom of the D. We can make a D.
Is this good? Is this D?
Whoa, someone needs to leave. Leave, leave, leave!
Biboo, move! Biboo, move!
Is her tail in the way?
Why is this...
That's good enough! That's good enough! That's a D!
E! Let's make a big E!
Wait, aren't we supposed to do V?
Okay, Mococo, you're not Mococo... Fuwawa!
Be the tall back. Come here, come here.
What letter are we on?
V! V! V!
V!
No, no, you stay there.
We got this, we got this!
Oh!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, we could be...
Yeah, yeah, like this, yeah, yeah.
E! We got E! We got E!
Okay, E, A, D, B. Okay, I'll be the middle, I'll be the middle E.
You'll be the tall?
The tall? I'll be the tall. Okay, I'll sit down.
Someone needs to be the bottom. I'll be the bottom.
You have to go...
How about this one?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
Arms out like this.
Wait...
Is this an E?
It's supposed to be an E, I don't know why Shiori is all the way there though.
You have to crouch, you have to crouch! You have to crouch!
You have to crouch, you have to crouch!
Okay, okay, okay.
There! E! E! That's a very weird E, but it's E.
Lower your head a little bit.
Lower your head, there we go, E!
It's perfect! E! Yeah! Yeah!
Is this backwards?
Okay, it's fine, don't worry.
N! N!
Okay, okay, N. Two, two strong pillars, who are the tallest?
I'll be a pillar. I'll be a pillar. I'll be a pillar. Okay.
Wait, wait, let's put one, one, one person in front.
Okay, okay.
Sorry, she's been waiting for this all day.
Huh? Is this an N?
Yeah, yeah, this is good, this is good.
Get closer.
It's an N! It's an N!
Yeah! N!
Okay, D! Yeah!
Okay, what's next? T!
Overlap, overlap.
Wait, we have to be the front...
We're in one line.
My T is too strong, I'll just be a... I'll be a pillar. I'll be a pillar.
I'll be a pillar.
T!
T! Yeah!
We did it!
We proved our nakama power to the world!
Power of nakama!
And we overcame the shadows, so...
Now I think it's time to move on.
Oh, I kind of like how the shadows look together.
Shadow souls, I think.
We were super cute, right?
All right, let's go! Let's go!
We overcame the challenge.
Yes.
Let's continue.
Yes!
I was always looking for a beacon in the dark times;
My guiding light.
All the captive dreams I held so dear,
Waiting for a moment to live without fear.
Ever since I met you, we've been living in the sunshine,
So warm, so bright.
My heart is full, the skies are clear,
The road goes on forever, we made it so far together.
This is our song,
A story forged in bonds.
A journey of the heart that goes on and on...
Now I feel so free,
I can be who I am,
I know I'm not alone, I got a new life
In the rain, the wind, and the sunlight
You believed in me, and that's where it all began
Now hope is everlasting
I can live my life with you, unchained.
遥か遠くから
From far, far away
辿り着いた
We have finally arrived
輝きたたえる
Praising the radiance
よすがへ降り立つ
We land upon our haven
We're unchained.
I was shut away, I waited every day,
My whole world was so small
But here and now, it's like the walls just fall away;
I can see it all.
Out here in the light with you,
It's such a perfect view;
Blue skies and sunsets.
The joyful days that seem to fly,
The heartfelt moments and the good times,
And through all these years,
Through tenderness and tears,
I found my way at last,
'Cause I knew you were right here.
Now I feel so free
I can be who I am.
I'm not afraid, 'cause even on a dark night,
I can feel the glow of the starlight.
Now the world I see is as bright as you became.
I will cherish every moment,
this is what it means to live unchained.
Don't cry, you can breathe free;
I'm here if you need me.
Let go of all your heartache,
we made it through, it's the dawning of a new day
Feel the world's embrace,
oh, what a joyful place
This is where I wanna be, so come with me;
keep dreaming...
Now I feel so free,
I can be who I am,
I know I'm not alone, I got a new life
In the rain, the wind, and the sunlight
You believed in me, and that's where it all began
Now hope is everlasting
I can live my life with you, unchained.
遥か 遠く から
From far away,
辿り着いた
we arrived at last,
輝きたたえる
embracing the shining light,
よすがへ降り立つ
landing at our sanctuary.
We're unchained.
Oh my god, thank you! Thank you so much, everyone!
And that was Unchained for the very first time!
Thank you! We're so happy to be able to perform it for you all today.
But, but, but, not just that! There's other songs from the story of Advent that we've performed!
Yeah, our original songs!
Yeah, we've got a lot of original songs now.
I know, I think... I think my favorite has to be...
What Goes Around!
I like 'What Goes Around' too, it's sassy!
But we also have like 'Genesis'!
Genesis is amazing too!
I... I like 'Break Out'.
Oh, you like 'Break Out'?
I love 'Break Out'!
And you know the choreo!
Break out! Break out! Break out!
Our third anniversary!
All of a sudden! Our third anniversary!
I can't believe it's three years already together with you guys and with the Adventurers!
Yeah, three years strong together! The Advent show together, it's flown by so fast!
And we'll have many more years!
Thank you so much, Adventurers, for always being here during our silly times, playing this and that game together,
And all the Gnomes!
Yeah, Gnomes! Gnomes!
And our really special, original songs and covers this year!
And we're looking forward to all the new heights that hopefully we'll be able to reach together with you, and all of our milestones!
Let's keep aiming for the stars!
And we're going to grow taller!
Yeah, we're going to grow taller!
Speaking of the next step... how about we present our new original song,
Spotlight!
Get the mics, hit the lights, race ya to the stage!
Check, one, two! Now we're on the way -
Take a deep breath, this is our moment
We can make it, we're chasin' after greatness.
Watch the curtain rise (goin' up, goin' up)
Feel electrified (never stop, never stop)
Mm, we got that vibe
Yeah, you know that's right
Gotta keep it hype, It's our time!
No more fear (feel alive)
I'm right here (by your side)
Cue me in and let the music play, take it away!
Come on! Steal a little spotlight (spotlight!)
I wanna see you shine bright (shine bright!)
Now you're ready for the big time (big time!)
Raise up your voice, it's all right
Steal a little spotlight (spotlight!)
It hits ya like a bullseye
Bullseye!
You gotta chase it for your whole life
so run with all of your might
to the spotlight
Play that rhythm, they won't know what hit 'em
Gonna be unforgettable
so much fun, it's criminal
We keep plotting to steal the show, oh yeah
On your mark, and ready, set, go go!
Oh, we never miss
What a bop, what a bop
Yeah, we're loving this
Keep it up, keep it up
Take it all in, this is who we are
in the dark, we shine like stars!
No more tears
here we are
Feel those cheers
in your heart
Let the whole world know it's you and me
finally free
come on!
Steal a little spotlight
I wanna see you shine bright
Now you're ready for the big time
Raise up your voice, it's all right
Steal a little spotlight
It hits ya like a bullseye
Bullseye!
You gotta chase it for your whole life
so run with all of your might
Steal that spotlight
Aura farming baddies in a getaway car,
Rizz 'em up and never stop, gonna be stars
Breakin' out, breakin' rules, joking like it's April Fool's,
Ooh...
Like a moth to a flame
You been caught, welcome to our game
It's your move, wanna play?
You're confused, goin' renegade?
Advent, yeah, that's right
Advent, steal that spotlight
Life's sweeter on the run, just having fun!
One, two, three, four!
Ooh...
Steal a little spotlight
Spotlight!
I wanna see you shine bright
Shine bright!
Now you're ready for the big time
Big time!
Raise up your voice, it's all right
Steal a little spotlight
spotlight!
It hits ya like a bullseye
Bullseye!
You gotta chase it for your whole life
so run with all of your might
to the spotlight
Steal the spotlight, steal the spotlight,
steal the spotlight
Now we're really rockin'!
Steal the spotlight, steal the spotlight,
steal the spotlight
Run with all your might...
Steal the spotlight, steal the spotlight,
steal the spotlight
Now I think you got it
steal the spotlight, steal the spotlight,
steal the spotlight
All right!
Yeah!
That was our newest song, Spotlight! Spotlight!
Yay! Spotlight! Spotlight!
We are aura farming baddies in a getaway car!
Advent! Steal that spotlight!
Wait, wait, wait, I've heard this... This song sounds familiar.
No, no, no! This is completely new!
Yeah! It's our original song!
Yeah, this is our original today!
Yeah, we are senpais!
That's right, that's right!
We are the aura farming baddies in a getaway car!
Oh my gosh! Yeah!
Please listen to Advent's newest song, Spotlight! Lots and lots, okay?
Over and over!
Ooh! Familiar...
Um, well...
...if we can, since we're getting close to the end, maybe we should make some individual announcements.
Who wants to start? Go ahead, Nerissa!
So, I'll start!
So, while we don't have any Advent joint merch, I believe all of us will probably have anniversary merch,
and I am no exception!
I have, I think the highlight item this year...
...is a dakimakura!
Whoaa! Oh my gosh!
Double-sided with the office lady and my pajama outfit, so please look forward to it!
Office lady by day!
And then, I've also had a new cover come out recently...
...of a song that we just performed here today, Bad Apple!
In English, so please listen to it!
Yay! Woohoo!
And Koseki Bijou!
Ooh, what you got?
Okay! She's awake, she's awake!
Hey everyone! Uh, Bijou just released a new VR Chat room...
...and you might want to check it out because it's pretty cool. We got a little...
...arcade bar thing going around. Come on in and visit!
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Come visit!
And also, I know, uh, Bijou's a little bit kind of...
...close to like a million subscribers!
Yay! So close!
So, so maybe if you could subscribe to my channel, I would be a little, you know...
...hee-hee tee-hee, a little happy!
Aw! Yes, everyone should subscribe! Yeah! Hurry, hurry!
And Shiori is next!
イェーイ！
Yay!
シオリ！
Shiori!
私だよ！
That's me!
チャンネル登録と高評価、よろしくお願いします！
And make sure you guys subscribe and like this video!
イェーイ！ チャンネル登録して！
Yeah! Hit subscribe!
ボタンを押して！ボタンを押して！
Hit the button! Hit the button!
でっかいのを... ベルを鳴らして！
Hit the big... bell ring!
通知ボタンね！コメントして、チャンネル登録も！
The notification button, yeah! Leave a comment, subscribe!
やって！やって！やってみて！
Do it! Do it! Do the thing, do the thing!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
次は！
Next up!
あれ？何？
Huh? What?
もこちゃん、そうだ！FUWAMOCO！
Mococo-chan, that's right! FUWAMOCO!
イェーイ！そして最近...
Yeah! And recently...
私たちの新オリジナルソング「めくるめくランデヴー」をリリースしました！
We released a brand-new original song, "Mekurumeku Rendezvous"!
アニメのエンディングテーマでもあるんだよ！
Also the ending theme for an anime!
だからぜひチェックしてね！
So please go check it out!
あと、近いうちに重大発表もあるよ！
We also have a big announcement really soon!
重大発表！楽しみにしててね、いい？
Big announcement! Please look forward to that, okay?
うん、オッケー！
Yeah, okay!
次！
Next!
そして、シオリ！私だよ、うん！
And, Shiori! That's me, mhm!
ホロライブAdventのシオリ・ノヴェラとして、ミニビジュアル漫画シリーズを始めました！
For Shiori Novella of Hololive Advent, I started a mini visual manga series!
おおー！やったー！
Oooh! Yes!
最初の2話はもう公開されてるよ！
The first two episodes are already out!
え？もう？！嘘でしょ！すごい！
What? Already?! No way! Wow!
本当に？！
Really?!
うん！
Yeah!
日本語と韓国語の字幕も付いてるよ！
But it has Japanese and Korean subtitles!
これからも続くから、時間がある時に見てね！
And there will be more to come, so please tune in when you can!
楽しみ！ワクワクする！
Excited! Get excited!
うわあ！
Woah!
今日はここまでだけど...
That's it for today, but...
もう終わりなんて信じられない！
Aw, I can't believe it's almost over!
でも、でもAdventはこれからも前に進み続けます...
But, but Advent continues to go forward...
...みんなと一緒に次のトラックへ！
...together with you to the next track!
これからも応援よろしくお願いします...
Please continue to cheer us on...
...そして、この旅を続けようね、いい？
...and let's continue this journey, okay?
イェーイ！行こう！
Yeah! Let's go!
よし、そして...
Okay, and now...
ハグタイムだよ！Advent一丸となって！
It's hug time! Advent strong together!
うん、Advent一緒だね！
Yes, Advent together!
あれ、ハグタイム？！ハグタイム！
Wait, hug time?! Hug time!
ハグタイム！
Hug time!
待って、ハグのポーズ？よし、ポーズしよう！
Wait, we're doing the hug pose? Okay, let's pose!
Advent... Strong！
Advent... Strong!
バイバイ！イェーイ！
Bye bye! Yeah!
よし、おいで、おいで！
Okay, group hug, group hug! Come here, come here!
グループハグ！グループハグ！大丈夫？
Group hug! Group hug! Are you okay?
すっごく可愛い！グループハグ！
You're so cute! Group hug!
あ、待って！可愛い！
Ah, wait! Cute!
ちょっと助けて！助けて！ダメ、いて！
Wait, help! Help! No, stay!
バイバイ！
Bye bye!